Daniel Wegmann

10 years of experience in fast paced financial markets. I have a passion for technology and made a transition to software engineering. Self starter, motivated, with good communication skills and able to work under pressure while being results focused, I'll be an asset to your team.

+1 (646) 363-9236 daniel.wegmann@gmail.com https://github.com/daniel10012 https://www.linkedin.com/in/da nielwegmann/

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Yoopies Project — Custom API built in Flask serving open data on french salaries available only in csv format. A JavaScript frontend and a map enable data visualisation. This was made to help a company better target its marketing efforts.

- Built with: Python, Flask, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, Leaflet, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Heroku
- https://github.com/daniel10012/yoopies

Blockchain Django Project — Website interactively showing how a simple blockchain works. Visualisation of hashing and linking data on different blocks with proof of work implementation.

- Built with: Python, Django, EC2, RDS, PostgreSQL, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap
- https://github.com/daniel10012/blockchain project

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sunrise Brokers (BGC Partners) — New York — *Stock Broker* MAR 2016 - MAR 2019

- Responsible for equity derivative vanilla and exotic business
- Covering the US and Latam

Various brokers and banks — New York — Commodities Broker 2012 - 2016

- Managed the crude oil derivative desk
- Pricing, trading and sales of commodity options
- Strategy backtesting with VBA

EDUCATION

CodingNomads — Python Backend Engineering JAN 2019 - APRIL 2019

EdX Harvard — CS50 Introduction to computer science 2019

ESCP EUROPE — Paris — *Msc Market Finance* SEP 2010 - SEP 2011

DAUPHINE University — Paris — *BEc and MSc Finance and Economics*

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Core Language

Python 3, JavaScript, C, HTML, SOL

Databases

SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL

Infrastructure

AWS EC2, AWS RDS, Nginx, Gunicorn, Heroku

Frameworks

Django (API, MVC (MTV), Security), Flask

Project Management

Trello, Agile development, Scrum

Version Control

Git. Github

Operating Systems

Linux, Unix

Additional Tools & Skills

Adaptable, love solving problems, curious

OTHER INTERESTS

Skydiving, Snowboarding, Surfing, Motorbike, Saxophone, Piano

SEP 2009 - SEP 2010